<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-center on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/data-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-center on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/data-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Center Topologies</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</guid>
      <description>[TOC]
The network topologies can be classified into tree and non-tree based topologies. This is very common observation in topology. There is another way to connect nodes are direct and indirect.
Indirect Topologies Tree The tree topologies are simple and broadly used in data center networks. Tree topologies may have either two or three levels. In a two-level tree, switches at the core level connect the switches at the lower level, which are referred to as edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos Networks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Blocking Network Non-Blocking Network Two Stage Non-Blocking Network Three Stage Non-Blocking Network Clos Network 5 Stage Clos Network FAT-Tree  In new era of internet, more applications are moving to cloud. Even for the standalone application, the central processing is done in cloud. Most of the cloud companies developed NextGen datacentre with CLOS architecture. This article is to demystify the Clos architecture.
The Clos grows in a very consistent way, thanks to having what&amp;rsquo;s called a scale-out architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics - Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics – Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
