<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/categories/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 19:14:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/categories/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Summary - Scaling Data Center Networks | Between 0x2 Nerds</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2024-09-26-podcast-summary-scaling-data-center-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2024-09-26-podcast-summary-scaling-data-center-networks/</guid>
      <description>Podcast - Scaling Data Center Networks - Dmitry Afanasiev Summary: 🎙️ Introduction to Scaling in Data Centers: Hosts introduce the topic of scaling challenges in data centers, emphasizing this as a series of topics to be discussed over multiple episodes. 💻 Guest Speaker - Dmitry Afanasiev: Dmitry, a network architect from Yandex, explains the challenges Yandex faces in scaling their networks, which are similar to hyperscalers like Google or Amazon. 🏗️ Challenges in Scaling: The discussion covers issues such as failure domain limitation, MPLS in data centers, and managing large data center networks with advanced technologies like RIFT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Podcasts &amp; TED Talks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Best Podcast Episodes of all time Naval Ravikant on The Knowledge Project&#xA;A deep dive on reading, happiness, decision making, habits, and mental models.&#xA;Elon Musk: Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot&#xA;A glimpse into what the future looks like, including Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot.&#xA;A deep dive into everything sleep by Matthew Walker&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I think that sleep may be one of the most significant lifestyle factors that determine your risk ratio for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
