<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-mental-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-mental-models/</guid>
      <description>Mental Models These two places where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the most useful mental models.
 Tools for better thinking (untools.co) Mental Model Examples (50+) That Will Make You More Successful (fronterablog.com)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethernet Optical Standards</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-03-12-ethernet-optical-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-03-12-ethernet-optical-standards/</guid>
      <description>The IEEE 802.3 Ethernet standards have been evolved exponentially. This is one of the driving force for the massive scale data centres, which is driving our cloud.
IEEE 802.3 Data Center Ethernet Optical Standards    Year Ethernet Speed Designation Optical Data Rate Wavelength Fiber Count MMF(km) SMF (km)     1987 10 MbE FOIRL 12.5 M 850 2 1 -   1993 10 MbE 10BASE-FB 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading List</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-my-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-my-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>Currently Reading  Coming Soon.  Engineering Books  Computer Networks: A Systems Approach (The Morgan Kaufmann Series in Networking) | Online/Free Copy - It explores the key principles of computer networking, using real world examples from network and protocol design.   Software-Defined Networks: A Systems Approach | Online/Free Copy - Software-Defined Networks (SDN) are transforming the Internet by replacing bundled, proprietary hardware and control software. SDN is being embraced by cloud providers, telcos, and enterprises, as it enables a new era of innovation in networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Center Topologies</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Indirect Topologies  Tree Fat Tree   Direct Topologies  All-to-All HyperX Flattened Butterfly Topology Torus DCell &amp;amp; DCube    The network topologies can be classified into tree and non-tree based topologies. This is very common observation in topology. There is another way to connect nodes are direct and indirect.
Indirect Topologies Tree The tree topologies are simple and broadly used in data center networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing backlog</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/writing-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/writing-backlog/</guid>
      <description>Topics in my writing backlog:
 How internet really works? Distributed systems in networking box Why C language is still exists and its competitor How do you measure your impact on the industry?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETCONF vs GNMI</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-01-31-netconf-vs-gnmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-01-31-netconf-vs-gnmi/</guid>
      <description>In the last article, NETCONF vs RESTCONF I have explained the difference between netconf and restconf and their use-cases. Netconf has very rich functionality, whereas restconf has matching functionality. Restconf has opened the door for the framework with REST-based system and infrastructure.
The gNMI (gRPC Network Management Interface) protocol comes from the openconfig consortium, a group of network operators led by Google, with the following mission - &amp;ldquo;OpenConfig is an informal working group of network operators sharing the goal of moving our networks toward a more dynamic, programmable infrastructure by adopting software-defined networking principles such as declarative configuration and model-driven management and operations&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book &amp; Paper Recommendations by smart folks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-books-reco-by-smart-folks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-books-reco-by-smart-folks/</guid>
      <description>Here are few book recommendations by smart people.   Book Recommendations, Holiday Book Recommendations by Gergely Orosz
  Book Recommendations by Will Larson
  Leadership Library by Philip Paetz
  Paper recommendations by smart people.  Technical Papers by Will Larson  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Blogs</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Eli Bendersky This guy is allrounder, this is a collection of various topic. “the C++ blog” - very good.
Appendix: related posts  Programming Blog by Dan Luu  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Books</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-books/</guid>
      <description>Programming Books Skiena; The Algorithm Design Manual The longer, more comprehensive, more practical. It&amp;rsquo;s similar in that it attempts to teach you how to identify problems, use the correct algorithm, and give a clear explanation of the algorithm. This also describess the real world programming.
McDowell; Cracking the Coding Interview Some problems and solutions, with explanations, matching the level of questions you see in entry-level interviews at Google, Facebook, Microsoft, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETCONF vs RESTCONF</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-07-netconf-vs-restconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-07-netconf-vs-restconf/</guid>
      <description>NETCONF vs RESTCONF
NETCONF is a protocol that was developed to provide a standardized interface to Network Element(NE)/Device to retrieve and manipulate configuration data.
Till now, CLI is the standard interface to interact with NE. but this is mainly for human. On the other hand, the NETCONF is mainly used for network automation.
CLI normally defined for human in user friendly way.
   Content Config, Oper Data     Operations &amp;lt;get-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;edit-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;copy-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;delete-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;lock&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;unlock&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;close-session&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;kill-session&amp;gt;   Messages &amp;lt;rpc&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;rpc-reply&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;notification&amp;gt;   Secure Transport SSH, TLS    RESTCONF is an HTTP-based protocol that provides a programmatic interface for accessing data defined in YANG, using the datastore concepts defined in NETCONF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is APIs?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-06-what-is-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-06-what-is-api/</guid>
      <description>What is APIs?
Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) are module: they take inputs and give you predictable outputs.   At its core, an API is a bunch of code that takes an input and gives you an output
  Sometimes, companies will make parts of their APIs publicly available, like github, Twitter or Google Maps
  In modern era, your favourite applications are collection of APIs.
  In WWW, the programmatic service is provided by the APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scaler - Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-10-web-scaler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-10-web-scaler/</guid>
      <description>These diagrams are self sufficient to explain.
Table of contents  1. Web Scaler 2. Consistent Hashing 3. Web Crawler 4. Unique ID Generator for Distributed Systems 5. Key Value Store 6. Rate Limiter 7. Youtube 8. Chat System 9. News Feed System 10. Google Drive  1. Web Scaler 2. Consistent Hashing 3. Web Crawler 4. Unique ID Generator for Distributed Systems 5. Key Value Store Ref: SSTable
6. Rate Limiter 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn C&#43;&#43; Programming in 1hr &#43; Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</guid>
      <description>Best Ever C++ Tutoriali for C Programmer
  Code Snip: Part1 | Part2 | Part3
Data Types | Arithmetic | If Statement | Switch Statement | Ternary Operator | Arrays | For Loop | While Loop | Do While Loop | User Input | Convert String | Strings | Vectors | Functions | Recursive Function | File I/O | Exception Handling | Pointers | Reference Operator | Classes / Objects | Private | Static Variables | Public / Encapsulation | Constructors | Static Functions | this | Inheritance | Call Superclass Constructor | Execute Static Method | Virtual Methods | Polymorphism | Abstract Data Type</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think? Part-II</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  The Farnam Street - How to Think: The Skill You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Been Taught Zat Rana - Marcus Aurelius: Thinking Clearly Mayo Oshin - Elon Musks&#39; &amp;ldquo;3-Step&amp;rdquo; First Principles Thinking&amp;quot; Ed Boyden - Rules for How to Think   &amp;ldquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem, I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Albert Einstein
 We are very good at solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</guid>
      <description>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang Network programmability is directly linked to Software Defined Network (SDN). So, it is driven by real benefits like time and cost savings, reduction of human error, customization and innovation. The network programmability is now understood as a set of tools and best practices to deploy, manage and troubleshoot network device, but it&amp;rsquo;s way beyond that.
Network programmability is not new. From the screen scrapping, to bash and expect scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos Networks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Blocking Network Non-Blocking Network Two Stage Non-Blocking Network Three Stage Non-Blocking Network Clos Network 5 Stage Clos Network FAT-Tree  In new era of internet, more applications are moving to cloud. Even for the standalone application, the central processing is done in cloud. Most of the cloud companies developed NextGen datacentre with CLOS architecture. This article is to demystify the Clos architecture.
The Clos grows in a very consistent way, thanks to having what&amp;rsquo;s called a scale-out architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Routing &amp; Packet Forwarding Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Bridging and Routing L2 Forwarding L3 Forwarding VRF Overlays  1. IP in IP 2. GRE 3. VXLAN   Segment Routing Forwarding in NIC  The core routing and packet forwarding haven&amp;rsquo;t changed for decades and it is not going to change for next decade also. But, it is going to evolve due to market needs, specially data centres. At the same time, Silicon capacity, CPU power, NIC bandwidth, all have increased significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How productive are you in life?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Do the right thing Do the right way Prioritize Organize Routine Goal Love what you do Recreation Positive thinking &amp;amp; attitude Right Values  Productivity concept is always there in my mind, but never thought so deeply. Until recently, my friend Biplab asked me the questions:
&amp;ldquo;How do you feel at the end of a hard day? Do you feel satisfied, fulfilled, or disappointed? Are you productive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean and Readable Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Why is this important? What do we achieve? Principles  A good code must satisfy few requirements: it must produce correct results, for which it is written. Also, it should be readable and understandable by other developers. It should also follow few code principles. This is your professional responsibility that the code you write will be re-read by many other developers, who want to either understand or modify the code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
