<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Think? Part-II</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-23-how-to-think-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-23-how-to-think-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  The Farnam Street - How to Think: The Skill You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Been Taught Zat Rana - Marcus Aurelius: Thinking Clearly Mayo Oshin - Elon Musks&#39; &amp;ldquo;3-Step&amp;rdquo; First Principles Thinking&amp;quot; Ed Boyden - Rules for How to Think   &amp;ldquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem, I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Albert Einstein
 We are very good in solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</guid>
      <description>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang Network programmability is directly linked to Software Defined Network (SDN). So, it is driven by real benefits like time and cost savings, reduction of human error, customization and innovation. The network programmability is now understood as a set of tools and best practices to deploy, manage and troubleshoot network device, but it&amp;rsquo;s way beyond that.
Network programmability is not new. From the screen scrapping, to bash and expect scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos Networks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Blocking Network Non-Blocking Network Two Stage Non-Blocking Network Three Stage Non-Blocking Network Clos Network 5 Stage Clos Network FAT-Tree  In new era of internet, more applications are moving to cloud. Even for the standalone application, the central processing is done in cloud. Most of the cloud companies developed NextGen datacentre with CLOS architecture. This article is to demystify the Clos architecture.
The Clos grows in a very consistent way, thanks to having what&amp;rsquo;s called a scale-out architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Routing &amp; Packet Forwarding Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Bridging and Routing L2 Forwarding L3 Forwarding VRF Overlays  1. IP in IP 2. GRE 3. VXLAN   Segment Routing Forwarding in NIC  The core routing and packet forwarding haven&amp;rsquo;t changed for decades and it is not going to change for next decade also. But, it is going to evolve due to market needs, specially data centres. At the same time, Silicon capacity, CPU power, NIC bandwidth, all have increased significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How productive are you in life?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Do the right thing Do the right way Prioritize Organize Routine Goal Love what you do Recreation Positive thinking &amp;amp; attitude Right Values  Productivity concept is always there in my mind, but never thought so deeply. Until recently, my friend Biplab asked me the questions:
&amp;ldquo;How do you feel at the end of a hard day? Do you feel satisfied, fulfilled, or disappointed? Are you productive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean and Readable Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Why is this important? What do we achieve? Principles  A good code must satisfy few requirements: it must produce correct results, for which it is written. Also, it should be readable and understandable by other developers. It should also follow few code principles. This is your professional responsibility that the code you write will be re-read by many other developers, who want to either understand or modify the code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
