<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IETF - Yang Models</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-12-ietf-yang-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-12-ietf-yang-models/</guid>
      <description>IETF - Yang Models IP Basic YANG Models (Southbound) Inventory Interface IP ARP VRRP Time NAT Security AAA Northbound YANG Models Framework Services Topology IVY (Network Inventory YANG)  https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ivy-network-inventory-yang/ https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ivy-network-inventory-topology/  Rerefences
 https://www.ipv6plus.net/IPv6Plus/YANG-Models/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Observability</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-06-network-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-06-network-observability/</guid>
      <description>Network Observability  The Many Uses of Network Observability Connections 2024: Network Observability  Slides: Slides Recording: Recording    Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Data Center Networking for AI Clusters</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-01-evolution-data-center-networking-for-ai-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-08-01-evolution-data-center-networking-for-ai-clusters/</guid>
      <description>Data Center Networking for AI Clusters   The Evolution of Data Center Networking for AI Workloads by Kentik   Evolution of Data Center Networking Designs and Systems for AI Infrastructure by Sujal Das
 Evolution of Data Center Networking Designs and Systems for AI Infrastructure, Part1  Evolution of Data Center Networking Designs and Systems for AI Infrastructure, Part 2 Evolution of Data Center Networking Designs and Systems for AI Infrastructure, Part 3 Evolution of Data Center Networking Designs and Systems for AI Infrastructure, Part 4 (Final) RoCE: from humble beginnings to being a star in the world of AI networking today    Excellent Articles by Sharada Yeluri -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF - AI for Networking</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-07-30-ietf-ai-for-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-07-30-ietf-ai-for-networking/</guid>
      <description>IETF - Applicability of AI in the Network This is one of the hot topic in networking. There are side meeting in IETF also.
 IETF 118 Side Meeting IETF 119 Side Meeting IETF 120 Side Meeting  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF - Data Center Networking for AI Clusters</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-07-16-ietf-data-center-networking-for-ai-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-07-16-ietf-data-center-networking-for-ai-clusters/</guid>
      <description>IETF - Data Center Networking for AI Clusters There has been a significant rise in the popularity of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, leading to the design of data centers specifically tailored for large-scale AI model training. These advanced networks impose unique requirements for network topologies and interconnecting technologies.
 IETF 117 AIDC Side Meeting IETF 118 AIDC Side Meeting IETF 119 AIDC Side Meeting IETF 120 AIDC Side Meeting  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos IP Traffic between Leaf and Spine &amp; Tromboning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-07-clos-ip-traffic-between-leaf-and-spine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-07-clos-ip-traffic-between-leaf-and-spine/</guid>
      <description>Traffic tromboning is a phenomena in data center traffic configuration or service chaining, while some service is bottleneck for rest of the flows. The service chaining can be created between leaves and spines using VXLAN and VRF way.
This is the article written by Mario Baldi and Silvano Gai originally posted in Traffic Tromboning Why, What, Where, How, and How Not
Why do we have traffic tromboning? Network and security services have traditionally been deployed in front of a group of end hosts that share some common function and are topologically close: e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Packet Switching Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-06-various_switching_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-06-various_switching_techniques/</guid>
      <description>A History of Network Switches 1990s: Layer 2 Switches Network switches (switches for short) are the evolution of network bridges whose behavior was defined by the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) in the standard IEEE 802.1 to connect two or more Ethernet segments. Switch and switching are terms that do not exist in standards; they were introduced to indicate a multiport bridge.
Initially, switches were pure layer 2 devices that forwarded Ethernet frames without knowing their content and without modifying the frames, thus providing connectivity for the many layer 3 protocols deployed in those days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Progression</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-career-progression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-career-progression/</guid>
      <description>Self Improvement  How I optimised my life to make my job redundant - Troy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s point of view Write a brag document -  Get your work recognized: write a brag document You Are Your Own Best Hype Person Brag now, remember later: Document your accomplishments   Being visible - Why visibility matters Being Glue - If you stop doing those things, the team won&amp;rsquo;t be as successful. But now someone&amp;rsquo;s suggesting that you might be happier in a less technical role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Leadership Resources</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-technical-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-technical-leadership/</guid>
      <description>In general, technical leader and staff engineer are similar roles, just named differently at various companies. Here, techinical lead(er) and staff engineer will be used interchangibly.
General Resources  The Definition of a Tech Lead - Titles like Architect, Tech Lead, Team Lead and Engineering Manager provide endless confusion. This article explores the definition of the Tech Lead role The Well Rounded Architect - Acting as a Leader, Being a developer, Having a systems focus, Thinking like an entrepreneur, Balancing strategic with tactical thinking, Communicating well Thriving on the Technical Leadership Path - So what does the more strategic work of a very senior engineer look like?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Address Planning Manual</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-04-30-ipv6-address-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-04-30-ipv6-address-planning/</guid>
      <description>RIPE [Create an Addressing Plan] document contains recommendations for service providers requesting IPv6 address allocation plus links to several other documents. SURFnet [Preparing an IPv6 Addressing Plan Manual] covers most things one needs to know, including the use /64 everywhere recommendation. ISOC [IPv6 Address Planning: Guidelines and Resources] document goes even deeper. Definitely worth reading. ETSI [IPv6 Best Practices, Benefits, Transition Challenges and the Way Forward] APNIC [IPv6 Best Current Practices] covers IPv6 Addressing, transition technologies, guidelines for content, data centre, hosting, cloud service, and application service providers, enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Advices by Naval</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-04-08-advices-by-naval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-04-08-advices-by-naval/</guid>
      <description>Life Advices by Naval
These are notes to myself. Your frame of reference, and therefore your calculations, may vary. These are not definitions—these are algorithms for success. Contributions are welcome.
 Happiness = Health + Wealth + Good Relationships Health = Exercise + Diet + Sleep Exercise = High Intensity Resistance Training + Sports + Rest Diet = Natural Foods + Intermittent Fasting + Plants Sleep = No alarms + 8–9 hours + Circadian rhythms Wealth = Income + Wealth * (Return on Investment) Income = Accountability + Leverage + Specific Knowledge Accountability = Personal Branding + Personal Platform + Taking Risk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Standard Body And India&#39;s Initiative</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</guid>
      <description>Internet Standard Bodies  Internet Society (ISOC) - a non-profit organization founded in 1992 to provide leadership in Internet-related standards, education, and policy. ISOC is dedicated to ensuring the open development, evolution and use of the Internet and its architecture for the benefit of people throughout the world. IETF - Techincal Forum for ISOC. End Product is RFC, standards for internet protocols. Other policy and business aspects ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers), IGF (Internet Governance Forum) and RIRs (Regional Internet Registries) like APNIC (Asia Pacific Network Information Centre), RIPE NCC (Réseaux IP Européens Network Conrdination Centre)  Network Operators   NANOG - North American Network Operators&#39; Group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Promoted at Work | Steve Dennis</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-03-05-how-to-get-promoted-by-steve-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-03-05-how-to-get-promoted-by-steve-dennis/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Promoted at Work by Steve Dennis
7 Tips
 Understand what you want Understand the role Understand the environment Tell impact stories Proactively seek feedback Avoid the victim trap Own it  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networks, Buffers, and Drops</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-03-04-networks-buffers-drops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-03-04-networks-buffers-drops/</guid>
      <description>Networks, Buffers, and Drops - Deep Dive by ipspace.in
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>49 Questions to Improve Your Results | Josh Kaufman</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-23-49-questions-to-improve-by-josh-kaufman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-23-49-questions-to-improve-by-josh-kaufman/</guid>
      <description>49 Questions to Improve Your Results by Josh Kaufman
 Do I use my body optimally? Do I know what I want? What am I afraid of? Is my mind clear and focused? Am I confident, relaxed, and productive? How do I perform best? What do I really need to be happy and fulfilled?  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create luck</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-23-how-to-create-luck-by-swyx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-23-how-to-create-luck-by-swyx/</guid>
      <description>How to create luck? by Swyx
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Articles by First Round Review</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-16-interesting-article-by-first-round-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-16-interesting-article-by-first-round-review/</guid>
      <description>Best Articles by First Round
 How to Become Insanely Well-Connected From BigCo to Startup: 20 Tips for Evaluating Early-Stage Companies &amp;amp; Making the Leap 40 Favorite Interview Questions from Some of the Sharpest Folks We Know The ‘Adaptable Leader’ is the New Holy Grail — Become One, Hire One The Best Interview Questions We&amp;rsquo;ve Ever Publishedhttps://review.firstround.com/the-best-interview-questions-weve-ever-published These 13 Exercises Will Prepare You for Work&amp;rsquo;s Toughest Situations The Secrets to Designing a Curiosity-Driven Career Don&amp;rsquo;t Just Network — Build Your &amp;lsquo;Meaningful Network&amp;rsquo; to Maximize Your Impact  First Round Resources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Articles by Sahil Bloom</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-11-advices-by-sahil-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2023-02-11-advices-by-sahil-bloom/</guid>
      <description>Resonating Articles by Sahil Bloom
 How to Change Your Life in 1 Year How to Get Lucky The Power Speaking Guide The Ultimate Productivity Tool Life Lessons from 1,000 Years  The Think Day: Your Secret Weapon  Six thinking question* prompts I have found particularly useful (that you should steal!): What are your strongest beliefs? What would it take for you to change your mind on them? What are a few things that you know now that you wish you knew 5 years ago?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  How to Read an RFC The Tao of IETF  A Novice&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Internet Engineering Task Force
  Writing An IETF Draft: Formatting, Authorship, And Submissions, How To Submit Your Ideas To The IETF Internet-Draft authors resource site, Getting started, Guidelines to Authors of Internet-Drafts Contributing to the IETF - How to play your part, and how RFCs are made IETF Drafting in Markdown Format  Drafting in Markdown Syntax    India Centric Technology Standard Drive Organization  India Internet Engineering Society (IIESoc) Industry Network Technology Council (INTC)  Appendix-I  Internet Standard Body And India&amp;rsquo;s Initiative  Appendix-II - Technology Manuals  IPv6 Address Planning Manual  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make A Big Career Transition by Utkarsh Amitabh</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-12-28-make-a-big-career-transition-by-utkarsh-amitabh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-12-28-make-a-big-career-transition-by-utkarsh-amitabh/</guid>
      <description>A Career Transition Article by Utkarsh Amitabh
Summary:
Career transitions are like onions. They’re complex and there is usually a lot more to them than we see on the surface. Whether you are pursuing a passion or side hustle, confused about quitting your job for a new one, or just looking for a change, know that it’s not a straightforward decision. It requires careful planning and thinking through the why, the what, and the when.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Psychology Articles by Benjamin Hardy</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-12-05-advices-by-benjamin-hardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-12-05-advices-by-benjamin-hardy/</guid>
      <description>Resonating Articles by Benjamin Hardy
 &amp;ldquo;Impossible Goals&amp;rdquo; Are Easier and More Practical than &amp;ldquo;Possible Goals.&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s Why. Make Decisions Today That Will Impress Your Friends In 20 Years 10 Steps to Become a Millionaire in 5 Years (or Less) The Most Important Skill For Interacting With People 23 Smart Ways To Increase Your Confidence, Productivity, and Income How To Achieve Your 10-Year Plan In The Next 6 Months Why Most People Never Get What They Want Want To Become A Multi-Millionaire?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-mental-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-mental-models/</guid>
      <description>Mental Models These two places where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the most useful mental models.
 Tools for better thinking (untools.co) Mental Model Examples (50+) That Will Make You More Successful (fronterablog.com)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article on SR TI-LFA</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-25-ti-lfa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-25-ti-lfa/</guid>
      <description>APNIC article on SR TI-LFA by Ron Bonica.
SR TI-LFA: Segment Routing and Topology Independent Loop-Free Alternates
NANOG 79 Recording
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc Advices on Career</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-17-misc-advices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-17-misc-advices/</guid>
      <description>Few career advices, I leant over the years
Bite Tips
 Always learn Stay Humble You should be valued Be mindful to your risk tolerance Be discoverable Dont stay comfortable for too long Decisions are not permanent Run Marathon, not sprint People, not jobs, are permanent Try lots of different things  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Like an Athlete</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-08-20-learn-like-an-athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-08-20-learn-like-an-athlete/</guid>
      <description>  Athletes train. Musicians train. Performers train. But knowledge workers don’t. Learn Like an Athlete
  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>notes-to-self</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/quotes/notes-to-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/quotes/notes-to-self/</guid>
      <description>notes to self  The deeper you go, the better it gets.
  You&amp;rsquo;ll never regret a workout
  Gift time, not things.
  Everything will be different in six months.
  Write your goals down. Cross &amp;lsquo;em out. Write new ones.
  Email the people you admire and tell them that. It&amp;rsquo;ll make their day. And it&amp;rsquo;ll make yours when they write back.
  Learning is a lifelong process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Podcasts &amp; TED Talks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Best Podcast Episodes of all time   Naval Ravikant on The Knowledge Project
 A deep dive on reading, happiness, decision making, habits, and mental models.
   Elon Musk: Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot
 A glimpse into what the future looks like, including Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot.
   A deep dive into everything sleep by Matthew Walker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glimpse At Two Approaches To Segment Routing</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-06-03-glimpse-of-segment-routing-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-06-03-glimpse-of-segment-routing-approach/</guid>
      <description>A Glimpse At Two Approaches To Segment Routing
Topic Covered:
 SR-MPLS Vs. SRv6 SRv6 Adoption Challenges Hardware &amp;amp; Software Support For SRv6  Appendix:
by Clarence Filsfils
 What is SRv6 network programming? SRv6: Deployed use-cases SRv6 micro-instructions  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Small Projects</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-24-joy-of-small-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-24-joy-of-small-projects/</guid>
      <description>The Joy of Small Projects
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practice by Jason Shen</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-16-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-16-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice by Jason Shen
The Complete Guide to Deliberate Practice
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of unsolicited advices by Kevin Kelly</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-11-advice-by-kevin-kelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-11-advice-by-kevin-kelly/</guid>
      <description>Bunch of unsolicited advices by Kevin Kelly
Advice Set I
Advice Set II
Advice Set III
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Routing - new concept</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-18-semantic-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-18-semantic-routing/</guid>
      <description>New discussion in IRTF - Introduction to Semantic Routing
See the recording at 47 min.
  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of new(ish) command line tools</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-17-list-of-newish-command-line-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-17-list-of-newish-command-line-tools/</guid>
      <description>This is really awesome. New generation cmd line tools.
A list of new(ish) command line tools compiled by Julia.
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get your work recognized - write a brag document</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-04-get-your-work-recognized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-04-get-your-work-recognized/</guid>
      <description>In the job, if you do good work, it will be recognized. At the same time, it is important to remember, specially at the time of appraisal cycle. It will help you and your manager to present your case wisely. Instead of struggling to prepare a list of achievements when needed, it will be better to keep it updated once in every month. Julia Evans has written a good article on this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read a paper</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-23-how-to-read-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-23-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
 Read the abstract (if provided)* Read the introduction. Read the conclusion. Skim the middle, looking at section titles, tables, figures, etc.—try to get a feel for the style and flow of the article.   Is it methodological, conceptual, theoretical (verbal or mathematical), empirical, or something else? Is it primarily a survey, a novel theoretical contribution, an empirical application of an existing theory or technique, a critique, or something else?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve career growth</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-19-how-to-achieve-career-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-19-how-to-achieve-career-growth/</guid>
      <description>In general, you might want to grow in your software engineering career, but:
what does growth mean? how can you achieve it? who decides if you are ready to grow? where do you start?
  How to achieve career growth: opportunities, skills &amp;amp; sponsors
This is a very insightful article. It clearly depicts the importance of self-awareness and drive the grown by yourself.
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Yourself</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-16-managing-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-16-managing-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Managing Yourself by Subbu Allamaraju
Summary:
 You’re the CEO of yourself — a one-person enterprise — act like one As a CEO, every day, you get to decide how you’re going to invest your time, which is your primary fixed capital.  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethernet Optical Standards</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-03-12-ethernet-optical-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-03-12-ethernet-optical-standards/</guid>
      <description>The IEEE 802.3 Ethernet standards have been evolved exponentially. This is one of the driving force for the massive scale data centres, which is driving our cloud.
IEEE 802.3 Data Center Ethernet Optical Standards    Year Ethernet Speed Designation Optical Data Rate Wavelength Fiber Count MMF(km) SMF (km)     1987 10 MbE FOIRL 12.5 M 850 2 1 -   1993 10 MbE 10BASE-FB 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading List</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-my-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-my-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>Currently Reading  Coming Soon.  Engineering Books  Computer Networks: A Systems Approach (The Morgan Kaufmann Series in Networking) | Online - It explores the key principles of computer networking, using real world examples from network and protocol design.   Software-Defined Networks: A Systems Approach | Online | pdf - Software-Defined Networks (SDN) are transforming the Internet by replacing bundled, proprietary hardware and control software. SDN is being embraced by cloud providers, telcos, and enterprises, as it enables a new era of innovation in networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Center Topologies</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-02-26-dc-topologies/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Indirect Topologies  Tree Fat Tree   Direct Topologies  All-to-All HyperX Flattened Butterfly Topology Torus DCell &amp;amp; DCube    The network topologies can be classified into tree and non-tree based topologies. This is very common observation in topology. There is another way to connect nodes are direct and indirect.
Indirect Topologies Tree The tree topologies are simple and broadly used in data center networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Workspace For Productivity, Focus, &amp; Creativity</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-25-optimizing-workspace-for-productivity-focus-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-25-optimizing-workspace-for-productivity-focus-creativity/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing Workspace for Productivity, Focus, &amp;amp; Creativity by Juan Pablo Aranovich
Summary:
 Bright lights during phase 1 of the day. Place visual focus direct in front of you. Restricted visual window. Put screens at nose level (at least). Avoid reclining Half stand and half sited work. Avoid white noise. Pursue 40 hertz binaural beats during work bout or prior to work bout. Stationary tread mill increases alertness and focus. Cathedral effect: focused and analytical work: low ceiling space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCION vs. Segment Routing</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-14-scion-segment-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-14-scion-segment-routing/</guid>
      <description>SCION vs. Segment Routing
Book, papers, videos, tutorials - https://www.scion-architecture.net
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/blogroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/blogroll/</guid>
      <description>People &amp;amp; Blogs  Paul Graham - Essays Marc Andreessen - Pmarca Guide to Personal Productivity Morgan Housel Naval Ravikant Sam Altman - Idea Generation, How To Be Successful, The days are long but the decades are short Julian Shapiro - Blogs Sriram Krishnan Ryan Hoover Patrick Collison David Perell Tiago Forte Will Larson - Work on what matters, Systems Thinking, Some career advice, Resources for Staff-plus engineers, How to be a tech influencer, A forty-year career Gergely Orosz Julia Evans Elad Gil - &amp;ldquo;Career Decisions&amp;rdquo; (in Silicon Valley / tech) Ben Thompson - Every business school should have a course on Aggregation Theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books &amp; Blogs</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/books-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/books-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Books/Blogs  My Reading List Books Programming Blogs Mental Models Books &amp;amp; Paper Recommendation by smart folks  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engg Papers</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/engg-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/engg-papers/</guid>
      <description>Interesting Papers   Knowledge-Defined Networking public copy
 The research community has considered in the past the application of Artificial Intelligence (AI) techniques to control and operate networks. A notable example is the Knowledge Plane proposed by D.Clark et al. However, such techniques have not been extensively prototyped or deployed in the held yet. In this paper, we explore the reasons for the lack of adoption and posit that the rise of two recent paradigms: Software-Defined Networking (SDN) and Network Analytics (NA), will facilitate the adoption of AI techniques in the context of network operation and control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing backlog</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/writing-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/writing-backlog/</guid>
      <description>Topics in my writing backlog:
 How internet really works? Distributed systems in networking box Why C language is still exists and its competitor How do you measure your impact on the industry? Google&amp;rsquo;s Network Overview - Data Center(Jupiter), Backbone(B4), Control Plane(Orion), Networking Slicing and IETF Initatives - Description of Network Slicing Concept,  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETCONF vs GNMI</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-01-31-netconf-vs-gnmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2022-01-31-netconf-vs-gnmi/</guid>
      <description>In the last article, NETCONF vs RESTCONF I have explained the difference between netconf and restconf and their use-cases. Netconf has very rich functionality, whereas restconf has matching functionality. Restconf has opened the door for the framework with REST-based system and infrastructure.
The gNMI (gRPC Network Management Interface) protocol comes from the openconfig consortium, a group of network operators led by Google, with the following mission - &amp;ldquo;OpenConfig is an informal working group of network operators sharing the goal of moving our networks toward a more dynamic, programmable infrastructure by adopting software-defined networking principles such as declarative configuration and model-driven management and operations&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book &amp; Paper Recommendations by smart folks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-books-reco-by-smart-folks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-books-reco-by-smart-folks/</guid>
      <description>Here are few book recommendations by smart people.   Book Recommendations, Holiday Book Recommendations by Gergely Orosz
  Book Recommendations till 2018, 2019 - 2022 reading recap by Will Larson
  Leadership Library by Philip Paetz
  Paper recommendations by smart people.  Papers We Love Technical Papers by Will Larson  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-books/</guid>
      <description>Programming Books Skiena; The Algorithm Design Manual The longer, more comprehensive, more practical. It&amp;rsquo;s similar in that it attempts to teach you how to identify problems, use the correct algorithm, and give a clear explanation of the algorithm. This also describess the real world programming.
McDowell; Cracking the Coding Interview Some problems and solutions, with explanations, matching the level of questions you see in entry-level interviews at Google, Facebook, Microsoft, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Blogs</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/evergreen-programming-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Eli Bendersky This guy is allrounder, this is a collection of various topic. “the C++ blog” - very good.
Appendix: related posts  Programming Blog by Dan Luu  Appendix: Programming Language Benchmarks  Programming Language and compiler Benchmarks [Source Code] Which programming language is fastest? [Source Code]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise - Daily Desk Stretches</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-12-15-excercise-desk-stretches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-12-15-excercise-desk-stretches/</guid>
      <description>Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISP Design Guide</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-11-24-isp-design-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-11-24-isp-design-guide/</guid>
      <description>ISP Design Guide: Separation of network functions – introduction and overview by Kevin Myers
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETCONF vs RESTCONF</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-07-netconf-vs-restconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-07-netconf-vs-restconf/</guid>
      <description>NETCONF vs RESTCONF
NETCONF is a protocol that was developed to provide a standardized interface to Network Element(NE)/Device to retrieve and manipulate configuration data.
Till now, CLI is the standard interface to interact with NE. but this is mainly for human. On the other hand, the NETCONF is mainly used for network automation.
CLI normally defined for human in user friendly way.
   Content Config, Oper Data     Operations &amp;lt;get-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;edit-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;copy-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;delete-config&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;lock&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;unlock&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;close-session&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;kill-session&amp;gt;   Messages &amp;lt;rpc&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;rpc-reply&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;notification&amp;gt;   Secure Transport SSH, TLS    RESTCONF is an HTTP-based protocol that provides a programmatic interface for accessing data defined in YANG, using the datastore concepts defined in NETCONF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is APIs?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-06-what-is-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-11-06-what-is-api/</guid>
      <description>What is APIs?
Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) are module: they take inputs and give you predictable outputs.   At its core, an API is a bunch of code that takes an input and gives you an output
  Sometimes, companies will make parts of their APIs publicly available, like github, Twitter or Google Maps
  In modern era, your favourite applications are collection of APIs.
  In WWW, the programmatic service is provided by the APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scaler - Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-10-web-scaler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-10-web-scaler/</guid>
      <description>These diagrams are self sufficient to explain.
Table of contents  1. Web Scaler 2. Consistent Hashing 3. Web Crawler 4. Unique ID Generator for Distributed Systems 5. Key Value Store 6. Rate Limiter 7. Youtube 8. Chat System 9. News Feed System 10. Google Drive  1. Web Scaler 2. Consistent Hashing 3. Web Crawler 4. Unique ID Generator for Distributed Systems 5. Key Value Store Ref: SSTable
6. Rate Limiter 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn C&#43;&#43; Programming in 1hr &#43; Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</guid>
      <description>Best Ever C++ Tutoriali for C Programmer
  Code Snip: Part1 | Part2 | Part3
Data Types | Arithmetic | If Statement | Switch Statement | Ternary Operator | Arrays | For Loop | While Loop | Do While Loop | User Input | Convert String | Strings | Vectors | Functions | Recursive Function | File I/O | Exception Handling | Pointers | Reference Operator | Classes / Objects | Private | Static Variables | Public / Encapsulation | Constructors | Static Functions | this | Inheritance | Call Superclass Constructor | Execute Static Method | Virtual Methods | Polymorphism | Abstract Data Type</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think? Part-II</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  The Farnam Street - How to Think: The Skill You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Been Taught Zat Rana - Marcus Aurelius: Thinking Clearly Mayo Oshin - Elon Musks&#39; &amp;ldquo;3-Step&amp;rdquo; First Principles Thinking&amp;quot; Ed Boyden - Rules for How to Think   &amp;ldquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem, I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Albert Einstein
 We are very good at solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Negotiate</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</guid>
      <description>How to negotiate from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
You’ve done well in the interview. Now you have the recruiter calling you and reading out some numbers for you. What do you do? Here are some tips I give people.
 Always negotiate! The system expects you to. You’ll never be dinged for it as long as you do it right. Also - negotiating when you get hired is 10x easier than negotiating after you start as an employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less-known interview tips for interviewer</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</guid>
      <description>Few interview tips for interviewer from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
The macro point here is making the process as pleasant and fun as possible. It is unnatural to sit in a room being judged by another human so anything we can do to make it easier goes a long way.
  Show up on time.
  No calls/messaging/phone usage or side-conversations during an interview unless an absolute emergency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</guid>
      <description>Regret Minimization Framework by Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon
When you are facing a big potential change in life, such as switching jobs, starting a café, or moving to another place, don’t just look at all the small details. These details can come later. Instead, start by asking yourself: On my deathbed, will I regret not taking this chance?
To some, this might sound a bit morbid, but for me, it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</guid>
      <description>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang Network programmability is directly linked to Software Defined Network (SDN). So, it is driven by real benefits like time and cost savings, reduction of human error, customization and innovation. The network programmability is now understood as a set of tools and best practices to deploy, manage and troubleshoot network device, but it&amp;rsquo;s way beyond that.
Network programmability is not new. From the screen scrapping, to bash and expect scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom by Charlie Munger</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom from Poor Charlie’s Almanack by Charlie Munger.
  “Mimicking the herd invited regression to the mean.” If you do the same things as all the others, you cannot expect different results. Common plagues privately and professionally are status anxiety, social proof tendency, and the keeping-up-with-the-Joneses syndrome – doing what we can to be like the rest. It is not until you stop doing this, and instead find a unique way for yourself, that you will see other results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos Networks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Blocking Network Non-Blocking Network Two Stage Non-Blocking Network Three Stage Non-Blocking Network Clos Network 5 Stage Clos Network FAT-Tree  In new era of internet, more applications are moving to cloud. Even for the standalone application, the central processing is done in cloud. Most of the cloud companies developed NextGen datacentre with CLOS architecture. This article is to demystify the Clos architecture.
The Clos grows in a very consistent way, thanks to having what&amp;rsquo;s called a scale-out architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An incomplete list of skills senior engineers need, beyond coding</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</guid>
      <description>This is indeed good information by Camille Fournier blog post.
For varying levels of seniority, from senior, to staff, and beyond.
 How to run a meeting, and no, being the person who talks the most in the meeting is not the same thing as running it How to write a design doc, take feedback, and drive it to resolution, in a reasonable period of time How to mentor an early-career teammate, a mid-career engineer, a new manager who needs technical advice How to indulge a senior manager who wants to talk about technical stuff that they don’t really understand, without rolling your eyes or making them feel stupid How to explain a technical concept behind closed doors to a senior person too embarrassed to openly admit that they don’t understand it How to influence another team to use your solution instead of writing their own How to get another engineer to do something for you by asking for help in a way that makes them feel appreciated How to lead a project even though you don’t manage any of the people working on the project How to get other engineers to listen to your ideas without making them feel threatened How to listen to other engineers’ ideas without feeling threatened How to give up your baby, that project that you built into something great, so you can do something else How to teach another engineer to care about that thing you really care about (operations, correctness, testing, code quality, performance, simplicity, etc) How to communicate project status to stakeholders How to convince management that they need to invest in a non-trivial technical project How to build software while delivering incremental value in the process How to craft a project proposal, socialize it, and get buy-in to execute it How to repeat yourself enough that people start to listen How to pick your battles How to help someone get promoted How to get information about what’s really happening (how to gossip, how to network) How to find interesting work on your own, instead of waiting for someone to bring it to you How to tell someone they’re wrong without making them feel ashamed How to take negative feedback gracefully  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle of Competence</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Muner once said:
You have to figure out what your own aptitudes are. If you play games where other people have the aptitudes and you don’t, you’re going to lose. And that’s as close to certain as any prediction that you can make. You have to figure out where you’ve got an edge. And you’ve got to play within your own circle of competence.
If you want to be the best tennis player in the world, you may start out trying and soon find out that it’s hopeless—that other people blow right by you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cindrella Principle</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</guid>
      <description>At 31 years old, Charlie Munger was divorced, broke, and burying his 9 year old son, who had died from cancer. By the time he was 69 years old, he had become one of the richest 400 people in the world, been married to his second wife for 35+ years, had eight wonderful children, countless grandchildren, and become one of the most respected business thinkers in history. He eventually achieved his dream of having a lot of money, a house full of books, and a huge family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be good at sales?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneur Colin Dowling on sales, via HN:
  Sales is a lot like golf. You can make it so complicated as to be impossible or you can simply walk up and hit the ball. I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading and building sales orgs for almost 20 years and my advice is to walk up and hit the ball.
  Sales is about people and it&amp;rsquo;s about problem solving. It is not about solutions or technology or chemicals or lines of code or artichokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Routing &amp; Packet Forwarding Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Bridging and Routing L2 Forwarding L3 Forwarding VRF Overlays  1. IP in IP 2. GRE 3. VXLAN   Segment Routing Forwarding in NIC  The core routing and packet forwarding haven&amp;rsquo;t changed for decades and it is not going to change for next decade also. But, it is going to evolve due to market needs, specially data centres. At the same time, Silicon capacity, CPU power, NIC bandwidth, all have increased significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How productive are you in life?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Do the right thing Do the right way Prioritize Organize Routine Goal Love what you do Recreation Positive thinking &amp;amp; attitude Right Values  Productivity concept is always there in my mind, but never thought so deeply. Until recently, my friend Biplab asked me the questions:
&amp;ldquo;How do you feel at the end of a hard day? Do you feel satisfied, fulfilled, or disappointed? Are you productive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</guid>
      <description>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning
 A life-long program of self-study Keeping a diary/journal Scribbling notes immediately Keeping “indexed portfolios” (notes/summaries of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read or heard) Testing beloved concepts – make a note, immediately, if you come across a thought or idea that is contrary to something you currently believe. Absorb it, study it and don&amp;rsquo;t let it go until you conclude that you need to change your mind or if the thought or ideas is wrong Learning lessons by heart Seeking to earn the approval of great men (dead or alive) The humility to seek not fame (as in, wisdom flows into the humble man like water flows into a depression)  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean and Readable Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Why is this important? What do we achieve? Principles  A good code must satisfy few requirements: it must produce correct results, for which it is written. Also, it should be readable and understandable by other developers. It should also follow few code principles. This is your professional responsibility that the code you write will be re-read by many other developers, who want to either understand or modify the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics - Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics – Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</guid>
      <description>A set of 10 rules as listed in Ed Boyden’s popular blog post in MIT Technology Review, Nov 2007.
Managing brain resources in an age of complexity.
  Synthesize new ideas constantly. Never read passively. Annotate, model, think, and synthesize while you read, even when you’re reading what you conceive to be introductory stuff. That way, you will always aim towards understanding things at a resolution fine enough for you to be creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long time, I was keep thinking to write blog. But, always getting delayed due to fear, whether I am good at writing, or people will like it or not, etc. Finally, I overcome this fear and started writing from new year, 2020.
Just to give little background about me, myself, Prasenjit Manna, working with networking industry as programmer, developer, architect, influencer since 2000. My area of interest is always routing, switching, manageability, optical, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
