<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Article on SR TI-LFA</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-25-ti-lfa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-25-ti-lfa/</guid>
      <description>APNIC article on SR TI-LFA by Ron Bonica.
SR TI-LFA: Segment Routing and Topology Independent Loop-Free Alternates
NANOG 79 Recording
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc Advices on Career</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-17-misc-advices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-09-17-misc-advices/</guid>
      <description>Few career advices, I leant over the years
Bite Tips
 Always learn Stay Humble You should be valued Be mindful to your risk tolerance Be discoverable Dont stay comfortable for too long Decisions are not permanent Run Marathon, not sprint People, not jobs, are permanent Try lots of different things  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Like an Athlete</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-08-20-learn-like-an-athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-08-20-learn-like-an-athlete/</guid>
      <description>  Athletes train. Musicians train. Performers train. But knowledge workers don’t. Learn Like an Athlete
  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glimpse At Two Approaches To Segment Routing</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-06-03-glimpse-of-segment-routing-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-06-03-glimpse-of-segment-routing-approach/</guid>
      <description>A Glimpse At Two Approaches To Segment Routing
Topic Covered:
 SR-MPLS Vs. SRv6 SRv6 Adoption Challenges Hardware &amp;amp; Software Support For SRv6  Appendix:
by Clarence Filsfils
 What is SRv6 network programming? SRv6: Deployed use-cases SRv6 micro-instructions  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Small Projects</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-24-joy-of-small-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-24-joy-of-small-projects/</guid>
      <description>The Joy of Small Projects
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practice by Jason Shen</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-16-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-16-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice by Jason Shen
The Complete Guide to Deliberate Practice
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of unsolicited advices by Kevin Kelly</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-11-advice-by-kevin-kelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-05-11-advice-by-kevin-kelly/</guid>
      <description>Bunch of unsolicited advices by Kevin Kelly
Advice Set I
Advice Set II
Advice Set III
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Routing - new concept</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-18-semantic-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-18-semantic-routing/</guid>
      <description>New discussion in IRTF - Introduction to Semantic Routing
See the recording at 47 min.
  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of new(ish) command line tools</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-17-list-of-newish-command-line-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-17-list-of-newish-command-line-tools/</guid>
      <description>This is really awesome. New generation cmd line tools.
A list of new(ish) command line tools compiled by Julia.
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get your work recognized - write a brag document</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-04-get-your-work-recognized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-04-04-get-your-work-recognized/</guid>
      <description>In the job, if you do good work, it will be recognized. At the same time, it is important to remember, specially at the time of appraisal cycle. It will help you and your manager to present your case wisely. Instead of struggling to prepare a list of achievements when needed, it will be better to keep it updated once in every month. Julia Evans has written a good article on this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read a paper</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-23-how-to-read-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-23-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
 Read the abstract (if provided)* Read the introduction. Read the conclusion. Skim the middle, looking at section titles, tables, figures, etc.—try to get a feel for the style and flow of the article.   Is it methodological, conceptual, theoretical (verbal or mathematical), empirical, or something else? Is it primarily a survey, a novel theoretical contribution, an empirical application of an existing theory or technique, a critique, or something else?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve career growth</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-19-how-to-achieve-career-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-19-how-to-achieve-career-growth/</guid>
      <description>In general, you might want to grow in your software engineering career, but:
what does growth mean? how can you achieve it? who decides if you are ready to grow? where do you start?
  How to achieve career growth: opportunities, skills &amp;amp; sponsors
This is a very insightful article. It clearly depicts the importance of self-awareness and drive the grown by yourself.
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Yourself</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-16-managing-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-03-16-managing-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Managing Yourself by Subbu Allamaraju
Summary:
 You’re the CEO of yourself — a one-person enterprise — act like one As a CEO, every day, you get to decide how you’re going to invest your time, which is your primary fixed capital.  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Workspace For Productivity, Focus, &amp; Creativity</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-25-optimizing-workspace-for-productivity-focus-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-25-optimizing-workspace-for-productivity-focus-creativity/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing Workspace for Productivity, Focus, &amp;amp; Creativity by Juan Pablo Aranovich
Summary:
 Bright lights during phase 1 of the day. Place visual focus direct in front of you. Restricted visual window. Put screens at nose level (at least). Avoid reclining Half stand and half sited work. Avoid white noise. Pursue 40 hertz binaural beats during work bout or prior to work bout. Stationary tread mill increases alertness and focus. Cathedral effect: focused and analytical work: low ceiling space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCION vs. Segment Routing</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-14-scion-segment-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2022-02-14-scion-segment-routing/</guid>
      <description>SCION vs. Segment Routing
Book, papers, videos, tutorials - https://www.scion-architecture.net
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise - Daily Desk Stretches</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-12-15-excercise-desk-stretches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-12-15-excercise-desk-stretches/</guid>
      <description>Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISP Design Guide</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-11-24-isp-design-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-11-24-isp-design-guide/</guid>
      <description>ISP Design Guide: Separation of network functions – introduction and overview by Kevin Myers
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Negotiate</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</guid>
      <description>How to negotiate from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
You’ve done well in the interview. Now you have the recruiter calling you and reading out some numbers for you. What do you do? Here are some tips I give people.
 Always negotiate! The system expects you to. You’ll never be dinged for it as long as you do it right. Also - negotiating when you get hired is 10x easier than negotiating after you start as an employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less-known interview tips for interviewer</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</guid>
      <description>Few interview tips for interviewer from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
The macro point here is making the process as pleasant and fun as possible. It is unnatural to sit in a room being judged by another human so anything we can do to make it easier goes a long way.
  Show up on time.
  No calls/messaging/phone usage or side-conversations during an interview unless an absolute emergency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</guid>
      <description>Regret Minimization Framework by Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon
When you are facing a big potential change in life, such as switching jobs, starting a café, or moving to another place, don’t just look at all the small details. These details can come later. Instead, start by asking yourself: On my deathbed, will I regret not taking this chance?
To some, this might sound a bit morbid, but for me, it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom by Charlie Munger</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom from Poor Charlie’s Almanack by Charlie Munger.
  “Mimicking the herd invited regression to the mean.” If you do the same things as all the others, you cannot expect different results. Common plagues privately and professionally are status anxiety, social proof tendency, and the keeping-up-with-the-Joneses syndrome – doing what we can to be like the rest. It is not until you stop doing this, and instead find a unique way for yourself, that you will see other results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An incomplete list of skills senior engineers need, beyond coding</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</guid>
      <description>This is indeed good information by Camille Fournier blog post.
For varying levels of seniority, from senior, to staff, and beyond.
 How to run a meeting, and no, being the person who talks the most in the meeting is not the same thing as running it How to write a design doc, take feedback, and drive it to resolution, in a reasonable period of time How to mentor an early-career teammate, a mid-career engineer, a new manager who needs technical advice How to indulge a senior manager who wants to talk about technical stuff that they don’t really understand, without rolling your eyes or making them feel stupid How to explain a technical concept behind closed doors to a senior person too embarrassed to openly admit that they don’t understand it How to influence another team to use your solution instead of writing their own How to get another engineer to do something for you by asking for help in a way that makes them feel appreciated How to lead a project even though you don’t manage any of the people working on the project How to get other engineers to listen to your ideas without making them feel threatened How to listen to other engineers’ ideas without feeling threatened How to give up your baby, that project that you built into something great, so you can do something else How to teach another engineer to care about that thing you really care about (operations, correctness, testing, code quality, performance, simplicity, etc) How to communicate project status to stakeholders How to convince management that they need to invest in a non-trivial technical project How to build software while delivering incremental value in the process How to craft a project proposal, socialize it, and get buy-in to execute it How to repeat yourself enough that people start to listen How to pick your battles How to help someone get promoted How to get information about what’s really happening (how to gossip, how to network) How to find interesting work on your own, instead of waiting for someone to bring it to you How to tell someone they’re wrong without making them feel ashamed How to take negative feedback gracefully  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle of Competence</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Muner once said:
You have to figure out what your own aptitudes are. If you play games where other people have the aptitudes and you don’t, you’re going to lose. And that’s as close to certain as any prediction that you can make. You have to figure out where you’ve got an edge. And you’ve got to play within your own circle of competence.
If you want to be the best tennis player in the world, you may start out trying and soon find out that it’s hopeless—that other people blow right by you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cindrella Principle</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</guid>
      <description>At 31 years old, Charlie Munger was divorced, broke, and burying his 9 year old son, who had died from cancer. By the time he was 69 years old, he had become one of the richest 400 people in the world, been married to his second wife for 35+ years, had eight wonderful children, countless grandchildren, and become one of the most respected business thinkers in history. He eventually achieved his dream of having a lot of money, a house full of books, and a huge family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be good at sales?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneur Colin Dowling on sales, via HN:
  Sales is a lot like golf. You can make it so complicated as to be impossible or you can simply walk up and hit the ball. I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading and building sales orgs for almost 20 years and my advice is to walk up and hit the ball.
  Sales is about people and it&amp;rsquo;s about problem solving. It is not about solutions or technology or chemicals or lines of code or artichokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</guid>
      <description>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning
 A life-long program of self-study Keeping a diary/journal Scribbling notes immediately Keeping “indexed portfolios” (notes/summaries of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read or heard) Testing beloved concepts – make a note, immediately, if you come across a thought or idea that is contrary to something you currently believe. Absorb it, study it and don&amp;rsquo;t let it go until you conclude that you need to change your mind or if the thought or ideas is wrong Learning lessons by heart Seeking to earn the approval of great men (dead or alive) The humility to seek not fame (as in, wisdom flows into the humble man like water flows into a depression)  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics - Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics – Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</guid>
      <description>A set of 10 rules as listed in Ed Boyden’s popular blog post in MIT Technology Review, Nov 2007.
Managing brain resources in an age of complexity.
  Synthesize new ideas constantly. Never read passively. Annotate, model, think, and synthesize while you read, even when you’re reading what you conceive to be introductory stuff. That way, you will always aim towards understanding things at a resolution fine enough for you to be creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long time, I was keep thinking to write blog. But, always getting delayed due to fear, whether I am good at writing, or people will like it or not, etc. Finally, I overcome this fear and started writing from new year, 2020.
Just to give little background about me, myself, Prasenjit Manna, working with networking industry as programmer, developer, architect, influencer since 2000. My area of interest is always routing, switching, manageability, optical, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
