<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ietf on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/ietf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ietf on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/ietf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IETF - AI for Networking</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ai-for-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ai-for-networking/</guid>
      <description>IETF - Applicability of AI in the Network This is one of the hot topic in networking. There are side meeting in IETF also.
 IETF 118 Side Meeting IETF 119 Side Meeting IETF 120 Side Meeting  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Standard Body And India&#39;s Initiative</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</guid>
      <description>Internet Standard Bodies  Internet Society (ISOC) - a non-profit organization founded in 1992 to provide leadership in Internet-related standards, education, and policy. ISOC is dedicated to ensuring the open development, evolution and use of the Internet and its architecture for the benefit of people throughout the world. IETF - Techincal Forum for ISOC. End Product is RFC, standards for internet protocols. Other policy and business aspects ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers), IGF (Internet Governance Forum) and RIRs (Regional Internet Registries) like APNIC (Asia Pacific Network Information Centre), RIPE NCC (Réseaux IP Européens Network Conrdination Centre)  Network Operators   NANOG - North American Network Operators&#39; Group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  How to Read an RFC The Tao of IETF  A Novice&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Internet Engineering Task Force
  Writing An IETF Draft: Formatting, Authorship, And Submissions, How To Submit Your Ideas To The IETF Internet-Draft authors resource site, Getting started, Guidelines to Authors of Internet-Drafts Contributing to the IETF - How to play your part, and how RFCs are made IETF Drafting in Markdown Format  Drafting in Markdown Syntax    India Centric Technology Standard Drive Organization  India Internet Engineering Society (IIESoc) Industry Network Technology Council (INTC)  Appendix-I  Internet Standard Body And India&amp;rsquo;s Initiative  Appendix-II - Technology Manuals  IPv6 Address Planning Manual  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
