<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wisdom on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/wisdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wisdom on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 19:40:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Think? Part-II</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents The Farnam Street - How to Think: The Skill You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Been Taught Zat Rana - Marcus Aurelius: Thinking Clearly Mayo Oshin - Elon Musks&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;3-Step&amp;rdquo; First Principles Thinking&amp;quot; Ed Boyden - Rules for How to Think &amp;ldquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem, I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Albert Einstein&#xA;We are very good at solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</guid>
      <description>Regret Minimization Framework by Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon&#xA;When you are facing a big potential change in life, such as switching jobs, starting a café, or moving to another place, don’t just look at all the small details. These details can come later. Instead, start by asking yourself: On my deathbed, will I regret not taking this chance?&#xA;To some, this might sound a bit morbid, but for me, it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom by Charlie Munger</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom from Poor Charlie’s Almanack by Charlie Munger.&#xA;“Mimicking the herd invited regression to the mean.” If you do the same things as all the others, you cannot expect different results. Common plagues privately and professionally are status anxiety, social proof tendency, and the keeping-up-with-the-Joneses syndrome – doing what we can to be like the rest. It is not until you stop doing this, and instead find a unique way for yourself, that you will see other results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circle of Competence</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Muner once said:&#xA;You have to figure out what your own aptitudes are. If you play games where other people have the aptitudes and you don’t, you’re going to lose. And that’s as close to certain as any prediction that you can make. You have to figure out where you’ve got an edge. And you’ve got to play within your own circle of competence.&#xA;If you want to be the best tennis player in the world, you may start out trying and soon find out that it’s hopeless—that other people blow right by you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to be good at sales?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneur Colin Dowling on sales, via HN:&#xA;Sales is a lot like golf. You can make it so complicated as to be impossible or you can simply walk up and hit the ball. I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading and building sales orgs for almost 20 years and my advice is to walk up and hit the ball.&#xA;Sales is about people and it&amp;rsquo;s about problem solving. It is not about solutions or technology or chemicals or lines of code or artichokes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</guid>
      <description>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning&#xA;A life-long program of self-study Keeping a diary/journal Scribbling notes immediately Keeping “indexed portfolios” (notes/summaries of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read or heard) Testing beloved concepts – make a note, immediately, if you come across a thought or idea that is contrary to something you currently believe. Absorb it, study it and don&amp;rsquo;t let it go until you conclude that you need to change your mind or if the thought or ideas is wrong Learning lessons by heart Seeking to earn the approval of great men (dead or alive) The humility to seek not fame (as in, wisdom flows into the humble man like water flows into a depression) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Think?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</guid>
      <description>A set of 10 rules as listed in Ed Boyden’s popular blog post in MIT Technology Review, Nov 2007.&#xA;Managing brain resources in an age of complexity.&#xA;Synthesize new ideas constantly. Never read passively. Annotate, model, think, and synthesize while you read, even when you’re reading what you conceive to be introductory stuff. That way, you will always aim towards understanding things at a resolution fine enough for you to be creative.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
