<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogs on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/categories/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogs on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/categories/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn C&#43;&#43; Programming in 1hr &#43; Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-10-03-minimal-cpp-prog-manual/</guid>
      <description>Best Ever C++ Tutoriali for C Programmer
  Code Snip: Part1 | Part2 | Part3
Data Types | Arithmetic | If Statement | Switch Statement | Ternary Operator | Arrays | For Loop | While Loop | Do While Loop | User Input | Convert String | Strings | Vectors | Functions | Recursive Function | File I/O | Exception Handling | Pointers | Reference Operator | Classes / Objects | Private | Static Variables | Public / Encapsulation | Constructors | Static Functions | this | Inheritance | Call Superclass Constructor | Execute Static Method | Virtual Methods | Polymorphism | Abstract Data Type</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think? Part-II</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-09-25-how-to-think-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  The Farnam Street - How to Think: The Skill You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Been Taught Zat Rana - Marcus Aurelius: Thinking Clearly Mayo Oshin - Elon Musks&#39; &amp;ldquo;3-Step&amp;rdquo; First Principles Thinking&amp;quot; Ed Boyden - Rules for How to Think   &amp;ldquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem, I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Albert Einstein
 We are very good at solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Negotiate</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-12-how-to-negotiate/</guid>
      <description>How to negotiate from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
You’ve done well in the interview. Now you have the recruiter calling you and reading out some numbers for you. What do you do? Here are some tips I give people.
 Always negotiate! The system expects you to. You’ll never be dinged for it as long as you do it right. Also - negotiating when you get hired is 10x easier than negotiating after you start as an employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less-known interview tips for interviewer</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-09-11-tips-for-interviewer/</guid>
      <description>Few interview tips for interviewer from blog by Sriram Krishnan.
The macro point here is making the process as pleasant and fun as possible. It is unnatural to sit in a room being judged by another human so anything we can do to make it easier goes a long way.
  Show up on time.
  No calls/messaging/phone usage or side-conversations during an interview unless an absolute emergency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-24-regret-minimization-framework/</guid>
      <description>Regret Minimization Framework by Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon
When you are facing a big potential change in life, such as switching jobs, starting a café, or moving to another place, don’t just look at all the small details. These details can come later. Instead, start by asking yourself: On my deathbed, will I regret not taking this chance?
To some, this might sound a bit morbid, but for me, it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-22-network_programmability_snmp_or_cli_or_yang/</guid>
      <description>Network Programmability, which is preferred? SNMP or CLI or Yang Network programmability is directly linked to Software Defined Network (SDN). So, it is driven by real benefits like time and cost savings, reduction of human error, customization and innovation. The network programmability is now understood as a set of tools and best practices to deploy, manage and troubleshoot network device, but it&amp;rsquo;s way beyond that.
Network programmability is not new. From the screen scrapping, to bash and expect scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom by Charlie Munger</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-21-quotes-charlie-munger-almanack/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom from Poor Charlie’s Almanack by Charlie Munger.
  “Mimicking the herd invited regression to the mean.” If you do the same things as all the others, you cannot expect different results. Common plagues privately and professionally are status anxiety, social proof tendency, and the keeping-up-with-the-Joneses syndrome – doing what we can to be like the rest. It is not until you stop doing this, and instead find a unique way for yourself, that you will see other results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clos Networks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-08-15-clos_networks/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Blocking Network Non-Blocking Network Two Stage Non-Blocking Network Three Stage Non-Blocking Network Clos Network 5 Stage Clos Network FAT-Tree  In new era of internet, more applications are moving to cloud. Even for the standalone application, the central processing is done in cloud. Most of the cloud companies developed NextGen datacentre with CLOS architecture. This article is to demystify the Clos architecture.
The Clos grows in a very consistent way, thanks to having what&amp;rsquo;s called a scale-out architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An incomplete list of skills senior engineers need, beyond coding</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-08-03-incomplete-list-skills-for-senior-engineers/</guid>
      <description>This is indeed good information by Camille Fournier blog post.
For varying levels of seniority, from senior, to staff, and beyond.
 How to run a meeting, and no, being the person who talks the most in the meeting is not the same thing as running it How to write a design doc, take feedback, and drive it to resolution, in a reasonable period of time How to mentor an early-career teammate, a mid-career engineer, a new manager who needs technical advice How to indulge a senior manager who wants to talk about technical stuff that they don’t really understand, without rolling your eyes or making them feel stupid How to explain a technical concept behind closed doors to a senior person too embarrassed to openly admit that they don’t understand it How to influence another team to use your solution instead of writing their own How to get another engineer to do something for you by asking for help in a way that makes them feel appreciated How to lead a project even though you don’t manage any of the people working on the project How to get other engineers to listen to your ideas without making them feel threatened How to listen to other engineers’ ideas without feeling threatened How to give up your baby, that project that you built into something great, so you can do something else How to teach another engineer to care about that thing you really care about (operations, correctness, testing, code quality, performance, simplicity, etc) How to communicate project status to stakeholders How to convince management that they need to invest in a non-trivial technical project How to build software while delivering incremental value in the process How to craft a project proposal, socialize it, and get buy-in to execute it How to repeat yourself enough that people start to listen How to pick your battles How to help someone get promoted How to get information about what’s really happening (how to gossip, how to network) How to find interesting work on your own, instead of waiting for someone to bring it to you How to tell someone they’re wrong without making them feel ashamed How to take negative feedback gracefully  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle of Competence</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-circle-of-competence/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Muner once said:
You have to figure out what your own aptitudes are. If you play games where other people have the aptitudes and you don’t, you’re going to lose. And that’s as close to certain as any prediction that you can make. You have to figure out where you’ve got an edge. And you’ve got to play within your own circle of competence.
If you want to be the best tennis player in the world, you may start out trying and soon find out that it’s hopeless—that other people blow right by you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cindrella Principle</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-23-the-cindrella-principle/</guid>
      <description>At 31 years old, Charlie Munger was divorced, broke, and burying his 9 year old son, who had died from cancer. By the time he was 69 years old, he had become one of the richest 400 people in the world, been married to his second wife for 35+ years, had eight wonderful children, countless grandchildren, and become one of the most respected business thinkers in history. He eventually achieved his dream of having a lot of money, a house full of books, and a huge family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be good at sales?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2021-07-18-how-to-get-good-at-sales/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneur Colin Dowling on sales, via HN:
  Sales is a lot like golf. You can make it so complicated as to be impossible or you can simply walk up and hit the ball. I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading and building sales orgs for almost 20 years and my advice is to walk up and hit the ball.
  Sales is about people and it&amp;rsquo;s about problem solving. It is not about solutions or technology or chemicals or lines of code or artichokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Routing &amp; Packet Forwarding Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Bridging and Routing L2 Forwarding L3 Forwarding VRF Overlays  1. IP in IP 2. GRE 3. VXLAN   Segment Routing Forwarding in NIC  The core routing and packet forwarding haven&amp;rsquo;t changed for decades and it is not going to change for next decade also. But, it is going to evolve due to market needs, specially data centres. At the same time, Silicon capacity, CPU power, NIC bandwidth, all have increased significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How productive are you in life?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-15-how_productive_are_you_in_life/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Do the right thing Do the right way Prioritize Organize Routine Goal Love what you do Recreation Positive thinking &amp;amp; attitude Right Values  Productivity concept is always there in my mind, but never thought so deeply. Until recently, my friend Biplab asked me the questions:
&amp;ldquo;How do you feel at the end of a hard day? Do you feel satisfied, fulfilled, or disappointed? Are you productive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-12-20-charles-darwin-8-steps-to-steady-state-learning/</guid>
      <description>Charles Darwin’s 8 Steps to Steady-State Learning
 A life-long program of self-study Keeping a diary/journal Scribbling notes immediately Keeping “indexed portfolios” (notes/summaries of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read or heard) Testing beloved concepts – make a note, immediately, if you come across a thought or idea that is contrary to something you currently believe. Absorb it, study it and don&amp;rsquo;t let it go until you conclude that you need to change your mind or if the thought or ideas is wrong Learning lessons by heart Seeking to earn the approval of great men (dead or alive) The humility to seek not fame (as in, wisdom flows into the humble man like water flows into a depression)  Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean and Readable Code</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2020-11-18-clean-and-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents  Why is this important? What do we achieve? Principles  A good code must satisfy few requirements: it must produce correct results, for which it is written. Also, it should be readable and understandable by other developers. It should also follow few code principles. This is your professional responsibility that the code you write will be re-read by many other developers, who want to either understand or modify the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics - Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-10-01-link-state-protocols-on-data-center-fabrics-internet-protocol-journal-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Link-State Protocols on Data-Center Fabrics – Internet Protocol Journal (PDF)
Join my email list to get direct access to new blog posts.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think?</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-07-22-how-to-think/</guid>
      <description>A set of 10 rules as listed in Ed Boyden’s popular blog post in MIT Technology Review, Nov 2007.
Managing brain resources in an age of complexity.
  Synthesize new ideas constantly. Never read passively. Annotate, model, think, and synthesize while you read, even when you’re reading what you conceive to be introductory stuff. That way, you will always aim towards understanding things at a resolution fine enough for you to be creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/blogs/2020-01-01-first-post/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long time, I was keep thinking to write blog. But, always getting delayed due to fear, whether I am good at writing, or people will like it or not, etc. Finally, I overcome this fear and started writing from new year, 2020.
Just to give little background about me, myself, Prasenjit Manna, working with networking industry as programmer, developer, architect, influencer since 2000. My area of interest is always routing, switching, manageability, optical, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
