<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 16:53:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internet Standard Body And India&#39;s Initiative</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/internet-body-and-india/</guid>
      <description>Internet Standard Bodies Internet Society (ISOC) - a non-profit organization founded in 1992 to provide leadership in Internet-related standards, education, and policy. ISOC is dedicated to ensuring the open development, evolution and use of the Internet and its architecture for the benefit of people throughout the world. IETF - Techincal Forum for ISOC. End Product is RFC, standards for internet protocols. Other policy and business aspects ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers), IGF (Internet Governance Forum) and RIRs (Regional Internet Registries) like APNIC (Asia Pacific Network Information Centre), RIPE NCC (Réseaux IP Européens Network Conrdination Centre) Network Operators NANOG - North American Network Operators&amp;rsquo; Group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IETF</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/ietf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction How to Read an RFC The Tao of IETF A Novice&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Internet Engineering Task Force&#xA;Writing An IETF Draft: Formatting, Authorship, And Submissions, How To Submit Your Ideas To The IETF Internet-Draft authors resource site, Getting started, Guidelines to Authors of Internet-Drafts Contributing to the IETF - How to play your part, and how RFCs are made IETF Drafting in Markdown Format Drafting in Markdown Syntax India Centric Technology Standard Drive Organization India Internet Engineering Society (IIESoc) Industry Network Technology Council (INTC) Appendix-I Internet Standard Body And India&amp;rsquo;s Initiative Appendix-II - Technology Manuals IPv6 Address Planning Manual </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Podcasts &amp; TED Talks</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Best Podcast Episodes of all time Naval Ravikant on The Knowledge Project&#xA;A deep dive on reading, happiness, decision making, habits, and mental models.&#xA;Elon Musk: Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot&#xA;A glimpse into what the future looks like, including Neuralink, AI, Autopilot, and the Pale Blue Dot.&#xA;A deep dive into everything sleep by Matthew Walker&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I think that sleep may be one of the most significant lifestyle factors that determine your risk ratio for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/blogroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/blogroll/</guid>
      <description>People &amp;amp; Blogs Paul Graham - Essays Marc Andreessen - Pmarca Guide to Personal Productivity Morgan Housel Naval Ravikant Sam Altman - Idea Generation, How To Be Successful, The days are long but the decades are short Julian Shapiro - Blogs Sriram Krishnan Ryan Hoover Patrick Collison David Perell Tiago Forte Will Larson - Work on what matters, Systems Thinking, Some career advice, Resources for Staff-plus engineers, How to be a tech influencer, A forty-year career Gergely Orosz Julia Evans Elad Gil - &amp;ldquo;Career Decisions&amp;rdquo; (in Silicon Valley / tech) Ben Thompson - Every business school should have a course on Aggregation Theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books &amp; Blogs</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/books-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/books-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Books/Blogs My Reading List Technology Books Programming Blogs Mental Models Books &amp;amp; Paper Recommendation by smart folks </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engg Papers</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/engg-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/reading/engg-papers/</guid>
      <description>Interesting Papers Knowledge-Defined Networking public copy&#xA;The research community has considered in the past the application of Artificial Intelligence (AI) techniques to control and operate networks. A notable example is the Knowledge Plane proposed by D.Clark et al. However, such techniques have not been extensively prototyped or deployed in the held yet. In this paper, we explore the reasons for the lack of adoption and posit that the rise of two recent paradigms: Software-Defined Networking (SDN) and Network Analytics (NA), will facilitate the adoption of AI techniques in the context of network operation and control.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
