<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forwarding on Prasenjit Manna</title>
    <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/forwarding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forwarding on Prasenjit Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:14:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/tags/forwarding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clos IP Traffic between Leaf and Spine &amp; Tromboning</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-07-clos-ip-traffic-between-leaf-and-spine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-07-clos-ip-traffic-between-leaf-and-spine/</guid>
      <description>Traffic tromboning is a phenomena in data center traffic configuration or service chaining, while some service is bottleneck for rest of the flows. The service chaining can be created between leaves and spines using VXLAN and VRF way.&#xA;This is the article written by Mario Baldi and Silvano Gai originally posted in Traffic Tromboning Why, What, Where, How, and How Not&#xA;Why do we have traffic tromboning? Network and security services have traditionally been deployed in front of a group of end hosts that share some common function and are topologically close: e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Various Packet Switching Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-06-various_switching_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2024-04-06-various_switching_techniques/</guid>
      <description>A History of Network Switches 1990s: Layer 2 Switches Network switches (switches for short) are the evolution of network bridges whose behavior was defined by the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) in the standard IEEE 802.1 to connect two or more Ethernet segments. Switch and switching are terms that do not exist in standards; they were introduced to indicate a multiport bridge.&#xA;Initially, switches were pure layer 2 devices that forwarded Ethernet frames without knowing their content and without modifying the frames, thus providing connectivity for the many layer 3 protocols deployed in those days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Various Routing &amp; Packet Forwarding Techniques</title>
      <link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/writing/2021-05-30-various_routing_packet_forwarding_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Bridging and Routing L2 Forwarding L3 Forwarding VRF Overlays 1. IP in IP 2. GRE 3. VXLAN Segment Routing Forwarding in NIC The core routing and packet forwarding haven&amp;rsquo;t changed for decades and it is not going to change for next decade also. But, it is going to evolve due to market needs, specially data centres. At the same time, Silicon capacity, CPU power, NIC bandwidth, all have increased significantly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
